Finding Aid for the Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco Collection of Musical Works, ca.1920-ca.1980
UCLA Library, Performing Arts Special Collections
Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco Collection of Musical Works,
ca.1920-ca.1980
117
Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario
26 boxes (13 linear ft.)
University of California, Los Angeles. Library. Performing Arts Special Collections Los Angeles, California 90095-1575
This collection consists of published scores and reproductions of manuscripts
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Advance notice required for access.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of published scores and reproductions of manuscripts.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Music--Italy--20th century--Scores.
Collection Contents
  - 24 caprichos de Goya: para la guitarra. Ancona: Edizioni Musicali Bèrben, 1970. 4 vols. (26, 30, 34, 31p.). (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Revisione e diteggiatura di Angelo Gilardino. For guitar.
  - 24 caprichos de Goya: para la guitarra, op. 195. VII. Estan calientes. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 14 Febbraio [February] 1961. 5p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    For guitar.
  - 24 caprichos de Goya: para la guitarra, op. 195. XIII. Quien mas rendido? Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 24 Febbraio [February] 1961). 5p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 24 caprichos de Goya: para la guitarra, op. 195. XIX. Hilan delgado. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 12 Marzo [March] 1961). 5p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - II. Tal para qual. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 28 Gennaio [January] 1961). 6p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    From: 24 Caprichos de Goya. For guitar.
  - III. Nadia de conoce. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 29 Gennaio [January] 1961). 5p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - IV. Ni asi la distingue. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 4 Febbraio [February] 1961. 4p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - IX. Bien tirada esta. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 18 Febbraio [February] 1961). 5p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - V. Muchalchos al avio. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 5 Febbraio [February] 1961). 4p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - VI. El amor y la mueate. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 7 Febbraio [February] 1961). 5p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - VIII. Dios la perdone y era su madre. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 17 Febbraio [February] 1961). 4p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - X. Al conde palatino. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 18 Febbraio [February] 1961). 5p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - XI. Y se le quema la casa. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 19 Febbraio [February] 1961). 5p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - XII. No hubo remedio. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 20 Febbraio [February] 1961). 5p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - XIV. Porque fue sensible. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 22 Febbraio [February] 1961). 4p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - XV. Si sabra mas el discipulo? Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 26 Febbraio [February] 1961). 5p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - XVI. Brabisimo! Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 28 Febbraio [February] 1961). 5p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - XVII. De que mal morira? Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 2 Marzo [March] 1961). 4p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - XVIII. El sueño de la razon produce monstruos. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 4 Marzo [March] 1961). 6p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - XX. Obsequio a el maestro. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 7 Marzo [March] 1961). 4p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - XXI. Que pico de oro! Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 8 Marzo [March] 1961). 5p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - XXII. Volaverunt. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 14 Marzo [March] 1961). 4p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - XXIII. Linda maestra! Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 15 Marzo [March] 1961). 5p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - XXIV. Sueño de la mentira y inconstancia. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 18 Marzo [March] 1961). 7p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    From: 24 Caprichos de Goya. For guitar. ".. and here ends the second "Spanish journey"--ink, p.1.
  - Aria da Chiesa (sul nome di Ruggero Chiesa). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 12 Marzo [March] 1967). 3p. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    From Greeting Cards, op. 170. For guitar.
  - Ballatella (on the name of Christopher Parkening). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Nov. 10, 1963). 4p. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Brasileira (sul nome di Laurindo Almeida). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., March 14, 1967). 5p. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cancion Cubana (on the name of Hector Garcia). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (15-16 Ott. [Oct.] 1965). 5p. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    From Greeting Cards, op. 170. For guitar. 2 copies.
  - Cancion Venzuelana. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 2 Giugno [June] 1966). 4p. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Canzone Calabrese (sul nome di Ernest Calabria). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., March 25, 1967). 4p. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Canzone Siciliano (sul nome"Gangi"). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 30 Dicembre [December] 1962). 4p. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Les guitares bien tempérées: 24 préludes et fugues pour 2 guitares, op. 199. Florence: Bruzzichelli, 1974. 4 vols. (42p, 41p, 41p, 36p). (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Incl. second copies of vols. 1 and 2.
  - Sonatina canonica. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Luglio [July] 1961). 23p. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    For two guitars.
  - Sonatina canonica. Paris: Eschig, 1971. 17p. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Variations plaisantes: sur un petit air populaire (J'ai du bon tabac). Ancona, Milan: Bèrben, 1969. 12p. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Volo d'angeli. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 24 Marzo [March] 1967). 6p. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Volo d'angeli: sul nome di Angelo Gilardino. Ancona, Milan: Bèrben, 1967. 4p. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 24 Caprichos de Goya, op. 195: I. Francisco Goya y Lucientes, pintor. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 25 Gennaio [January] 1961). 5p. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    "..starting another journey through Spain.."--p.1. For guitar.
  - 3 Preludi Mediterranei, op. 176. Florence: Forlivesi, 1956. 13p. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Appunti, op. 210: Quaderno secondo: i ritmi. Parte III: Danze del Novecento. Milan: Suvini Zerboni, 1971. 36p. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Subtitle: Preludi e studi per chitarra.
  - Aranci in fiore. Milan: Ricordi, 1939. 6p. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Aria da chiesa: sul nome di Ruggero Chiesa, Op. 170, N. 43. Ancona, Milan: Bèrben, 1967. 2p. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Ballatella: sul nome di Christopher Parkening, Op. 170, N. 34. Ancona, Milan: Farfisa, 1965. 5p. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Brasileira: sul nome di Laurindo Almeida, Op. 170, N. 44. Ancona, Milan: Bèrben, 1967. 4p. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cancion Cubana: sul nome di Hector Garcia, Op. 170, N. 39. Ancona, Milan: Bèrben, 1966. 5p. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Cancion Venzuelana: sul nome di Alirio Diaz, Op. 170, N. 40. Ancona, Milan: Bèrben, 1966. 4p. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    For guitar. Two copies.
  - Canzone Calabrese: sul nome di Ernest Calabria, Op. 170, N. 48. Ancona, Milan: Bèrben, 1967. 4p. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Canzone Siciliana: sul nome di Mario Gangi, Op. 170, N. 33. Ancona, Milan: Bèrben, 1967. 4p. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Escarraman. No. III. El Villano (The country bumpkin). New York: Ricordi, 1959. 5p. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Series subtitle: A suite of Spanish dances from the XVI century. For guitar.
  - 1o Concerto (in Re) per chitarra e orchestra, opus 99. Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1954. 14p, 27p. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Solo part and piano reduction.
  - Japanese Print: sul nome di Jiro Matsuda, Op. 170, N. 46. Ancona, Milan: Bèrben, 1967. 4p. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Homage to Purcell, Op. 170, N. 38. Ancona, Milan: Bèrben, 1966. 4p. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Subtitle: Fantasia sui nomi di Ronald (1932) e Henry (1659-1695) Purcell. For guitar.
  - Ninna Nanna: a lullaby for Eugene, Op. 170, N. 14. Florence: Forlivesi, 1959. 3p. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    For guitar. 2 copies.
  - Passacaglia: omaggio a Roncalli, op. 180. Ancona, Milan: Bèrben, 1970. 11p. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Platero y yo (Platero and I), op. 190. Ancona, Milan: Bèrben, 1972-73. 4 vols. (38p, 33p, 37p, 40p). (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Para Narrador y Guitarra/for Narrator and guitar.
  - Preludio in forma di Habanera: sul nome di Bruno Tonarri, op. 170, no. 7. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 24 Marzo [March] 1954). 5p. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Rondel: on the name of Siegfried Behrend. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., March 20-21, 1954). 8p. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Rondo, op. 129. Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1958. 7p. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Edition Andrés Segovia. For solo guitar.
  - Serenade pour guitare et orchestra de chambre, opus 118. Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1956. 16p (part), 36p (piano). (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Edition Andrés Segovia. Arrangement for guitar and piano.
  - Sonata: pour guitare seule. Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1935. 15p. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Edition Andrés Segovia.
  - Suite: pour guitare seule, opus 133. London: Schott, 1954. 12p. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Tarantella: per chitarra. Milan: Ricordi, 1939. 9p. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    For solo guitar.
  - "Tonadilla" (on the name of Andrés Segovia). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., March 13, 1954). 6p. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Greeting cards, op. 170, Nr. 5.
  - Tonadilla sur le nom de Andrés Segovia pour guitare seule, opus 170, no. 5. Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1956. 4p. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Tre Preludi a Cicero, op. 194. Ancona, Milan: Farfisa, 1966. 8p. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    I. La grotta di Circe; II. Il porto di Ulissa; III. La tomba di Elpenore. For solo guitar.
  - Variations à travers les siècles. Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1933, 1961. 10p. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Variazioni (attraverso i secoli..) = Variations à travers les siècles. Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1933. 10p. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Estudio: per Chitarra (sul nome di Manuel Lopez Ramos). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., June 6, 1966). 5p. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Greeting Cards, op. 170, Nr. 42.
  - Estudio: sul nome di Manuel Lopez Ramos, op. 170, n. 42. Ancona, Milan: Bèrben, 1966. 4p. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Homage to Purcell (Greeting cards, op. 170, Nr. 38). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., June 20, 1966). 7p. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Subtitle: Fantasie on the names of Ronald (1932) and Henry (1659-1695). For guitar.
  - Japanese Print (on the name of Jiro Metsudo). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., March 23, 1967). 5p. (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Greeting cards, op. 170, Nr. 46. For guitar.
  - Passacaglia (omaggio a Roncalli), op. 180. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., April 16, 1956). 10p. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Platero y yo, para narrador y guitarra, op. 190. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. 28 compositions in 4 series. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Poem by Juan Ramon Jimenes. Various dates, from June 12, 1960 to July 21, 1960. First series: 1. Platero; 2. Angelus; 3. Retorno; 4. La Primavera; 5. El Pozo; 6. Gorriones; 7. Melancolia. Second series: 1. Amistad; 2. La Luna; 3. Juegos del Anochecer; 4. Ronsard; 5. El Loco; 6. La Tisica; 7. Nostalgia. Third series: 1. Mariposa Blancas; 2. Idilio de Abril; 3. El Canario Vuela; 4. La Arrulladora; 5. El Canario se Muere; 6. Idilio de Noviembre; 7. La Muerte. Fourth series: 1. Convalecencia; 2. Golondrinas; 3. La Flor del Camino; 4. Domingo; 5. Los Gitanos; 6. Carnaval; 7. A Platero en Cielo de Moguer. For solo guitar.
  - Romanza (sul nome di Oscar Ghiglia): Greeting cards, op. 170, nr. 37. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., 31 Agosto [August] 1964). 4p. (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Romanza sul nome di Oscar Ghiglia, op. 170, n. 37. Ancona, Milan: Farfisa, 1965. 4p. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    From "Greeting cards." For guitar.
  - Sarabande (on the name of Rey de la Torre): Greeting cards, op. 170, nr. 36. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., September 4, 1946). 3p. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Sarabande sul nome di Rey de la Torre, op. 170, n. 36. Ancona, Milan: Farfisa, 1965. 4p. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Tanka (Japanese song) on the name of Isao Takahashi. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., July 8, 1955). 5p. (Box 2, Folder 36)
    "Greeting cards, op. 170, Nr. 10." For guitar.
  - Tanka sul nome di Isao Takahashi, op. 170, n. 10. Ancona, Milan: Farfisa, 1965. 5p. (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Tarantella Campana: sul nome di Eugene di Novi, op. 170, n. 50. Ancona, Milan: Bèrben, 1967. 4p. (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Tarantella Campana (sul nome di Eugene Di Novi). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., March 30, 1967). 6p. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    "Greeting cards, op. 170, Nr. 50." For guitar.
  - Alghe (2). (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Angelus. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Alt Wien (Walzer, Notturno (2), and Memento Mori). (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Calma. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Candide. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - A Canon for Robin. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cipressi (2). (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Crinoline. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Epigrafe. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Etude. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Evangelicon (II - The Life, III - The Words, and IV - The Passion). (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Le Danze del re David. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Le Stagioni. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - b - a - b - a. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Cantico. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Lucertolina (3). (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Fandango. Published edition & Manuscript. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Fur Erna. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Homage to Paderewski. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - I Navaganti. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - La Sirenetta e il Pesce Turchino (2). (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - La Torre del Diavolo. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Media Difficolta (2). (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Melodia. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Mirages. Published edition & Manuscript. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Ninna Nanna del Dopoguerra. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Onde. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Passatempi. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Tango. Published edition & Manuscript. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Tre Poemi Campestri. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Vitalba e Biancospino. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - A Fandango for Escovado. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - The Stories of Joseph. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Toccata. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Two Film Studies. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Balow. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    2 copies
  - Bridal Song. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cherry Ripe. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The Day Is Done. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The Dove. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Endymion. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Happy Is England. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - I Sing of a Maiden. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    3 copies
  - The Knight of the Grail. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Nature. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - The Nightingale. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Old Meg. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Processional Song. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - That Ever I Saw. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - To One Who Has Been Long in City Pent. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Two or Three. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Amours de Ronsard, Books 1 and 2. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Bitter Lemons. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Children's Song. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Epilogue. Manuscript. (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Liberty, Mother of Exiles. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - The Mermaid Tavern. Manuscript. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Proverbs of Solomon. (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - The Seventh Day. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Sonnet CXXIX. (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Sonnet CLIV. (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Two Elegies, Il Cipresso and Le Armi del Valoroso. (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - A Seranade. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Boruch Habo. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - The Fountains Mingle with the River. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Homer. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Jock of Hazeldean. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Lament. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - The Light. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Lo, the Messiah (SATB, SSA, and TTBB). (Box 6, Folder 8)
    2 copies of each version
  - Mary, Star of the Sea. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Memorial Service for the Departed. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Mi Adir. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - The Moon. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - My Heart is Like a Singing Bird. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - The Nightingale. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - On the Grasshopper and the Cricket (3 copies). (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - One Word Too Often Profaned. (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - The Owl. (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Pibroch of Donuil Dhu. (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Psyche. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - The Queen of Sheba. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Remember Me. (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Sing No Sad Songs for Me. (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Songs of the Oceansides. (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - To Sleep. (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Two Songs of Praise. (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Uphill. (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Upon Westminster Bridge. (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - When the Lamp is Shatter'd. (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - The Word. (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - 2 Sonatas for Trumpet and Piano (Trumpet parts only). (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Concertino for Harp. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Concerto Italiano. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    copyist's ozalid master of violin part, copy of copyist's violin part, and printed full score
  - Larchmont Woods. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Sonata for Clarinet and Piano. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    2 copies of both piano and clarinet parts
  - Sonatina for Bassoon and Piano. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    2 copies piano score, I copy bassoon part
  - Sonatina for Flute and Guitar. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Variazioni Sinfoniche. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Violin Concerto No. 2. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Sonatina for Flute and Guitar. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Quintet for Guitar and Strings (Full Score). (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 2nd Trio (Violin). (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Capitan Fracassa. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Concerto Italiano. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - The Lark. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Notturno Adriatico. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Piano Quaintet No. 2 (Violin 1, Violin 2, Viola, Cello). (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Sea Murmurs. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - String Quartet No. 2 (Violin 1, Violin 2, Viola, and Cello). (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - String Quartet No. 3 (Full Score, Violin 1, Violin 2, Viola, and Cello). (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 1st Arabesque. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 2nd Arabesque. Published edition & Manuscript. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Figaro (vln & pf). (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Figaro (cello & pf). (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Humoresque. Published edition & Manuscript. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Hungarian Serenade. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Intermezzo. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Jeaux d'eau. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Meditation. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Rhapsody for Harp. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Sonata for Cello and Piano. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Suite 508. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Valse. Published edition & Manuscript. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Quintet for Guitar and Strings (Score). (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 2nd Trio in G (Violin and Cello). (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Piano Quintet No. 1 (Violin 1, Violin 2, Viola, and Cello). (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Sonata for Viola and Cello (Viola). (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - String Quartet No. 1 (Violin 1). (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - String Quartet No. 2 (Violin 2 and Cello). (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - String Quartet No. 2 (Violin 1, Violin 2, Viola, and Cello). (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - String Trio Opus 147 (Violin, Viola, and Cello). (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Trio in G (Violin and Cello). (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Il Bestiario: dodici poesie di Arturo Loria per canto e pianoforte, op. 188. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., April 20, 1960). 45p. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Text by Arturo Loria. For voice and piano. 1. Le Columbe; 2. Il Gufo; 3. Il Lombrico; 4. Il Moscon d'oro; 5. Il Muscoli; 6. Il Pipistrello; 7. Il Tarlo; 8. La Cicak; 9. La Marmotta; 10. Le Rane; 11. Le Rondini; 12. La Lucciola.
  - Leaves of Grass. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (15-30 Giugno [June], 1936). 35p. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    1. What think you I take my pen in hand?; 2. I dream'd in a dream; 3. Sometimes with one I love; 4. We two boys together clinging; 5. Are you the new person drawn toward me?; 6. When I peruse the conquer'd fame; 7. A glimpse; 8. This moment, yearning and thoughtful; 9. Trickle, drops!; 10. The base of all metaphysics. For voice and piano.
  - 1830: trois chansons par Alfred de Musset: Mises en musique sur des fragments. Milan: Ricordi, 1925. 13p. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    For voice and piano.
  - Aria of Ruth. New York: Mills Music, 1950. 5p. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    From the cantata Naomi and Ruth. For voice and piano.
  - Ballata (Messer Agnolo Ambrogini, detto il Poliziano). Naples: Curci, 1927. 7p. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    For voice and piano. 2 copies.
  - Briciole. Florence: Forlivesi, [1916]. 12p. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Text by Aldo Palazzeschi. 1. Rio bo; 2. Mezzogiorno; 3. Il passo delle Nazarene. For voice and piano.
  - Cinque poesie romanesche. Florence: Forlivesi, 1948. 13p. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Text by Mario dell'Arco. For voice and piano.
  - Girotondo dei geloso: per la lega dei gologsi del Giornalino della Domenica. Florence: Forlivesi, 1920. 6p. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Text by Renzo Simi. For voice and piano.
  - Indian serenade. Florence: Forlivesi, 1925. 6p. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Text by P. B. Shelley. For voice and piano.
  - La Barba Bianca. Florence: Forlivesi, 1924. 4p. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Text by Vamba (Luigi Bertelli). For voice and piano.
  - 4 Sonetti da "La Vita Nova". Florence: Forlivesi, 1927. 16p. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    1. Cavalcando l'altr'ier per un cammino; 2. Negli occhi porta la mia donna amore; 3. Tanto gentile e tanto onesta pare; 4. Deh, peregrini che pensosi andate. For voice and piano.
  - Le Roi Loys: ballata cavalleresca. Florence: Forlivesi, 1922. 13p. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Le Voyage. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Dec. 20, 1959). 4p. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Text by Joachim du Bellay. For voice and piano.
  - The Mermaid Tavern. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., May 1942). 5p. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Text by John Keats. For voice and piano.
  - My Betrothed: from Songs and processionals for a Jewish wedding. New York: Mills, 1951. 3p. (Box 11, Folder 15)
    Text: Hosea, Chapter II, verses 21-22. For voice and piano.
  - Ozymandias. Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., June 8, 1944). 4p. (Box 11, Folder 16)
    For voice and piano. "To Nick from Mario (who read this poem the day of the downfall of Mussolini..)"--ink, p. 1.
  - Sera. Naples: Curci, 1927. 2p. (Box 11, Folder 17)
    Text by Dante. For voice and piano. 2 copies.
  - Recuerdo. New York: Carl Fischer, 1941. 7p. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    Text by Edna St. Vincent Millay. For voice and piano.
  - The Shadow. New York: Carl Fischer, 1945. 7p. (Box 11, Folder 19)
    Poem by Ben Jonson. For voice and piano. 2 copies.
  - Shakespeare Sonnets Nr. XVIII ("Shall I compare thee.."). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., July 25th, 1944). 5p. (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Shakespeare Sonnets Nr. XXIX ("When in disgrace.."). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., July 31th, 1945). 5p. (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Sonnet Nr. CIX (William Shakespeare). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Sept. 17th, 1945). 5p. (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Sonnet Nr. VIII (William Shakespeare). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., July 22th, 1944). 6p. (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Shakespeare Sonnets Nr. XCVIII ("In the spring"). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Sept. 2nd, 1945). 6p. (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Sonnet LXXI (William Shakespeare). Ozalid copy of autograph ms. (Beverly Hills, Calif., Oct. 16-17, 1963). 3p. (Box 11, Folder 22)